Daniel South

Software Engineer (JavaScript, React, Node, Express, MongoDB, Next.js)

+44(0)7766 112137

southd12@gmail.com

LinkedIn

Bournemouth

Developer Portfolio: https://github.com/southyd12

I combine software engineering skills with a background in producing digital content for the BBC

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING SKILLS

- JavaScript: ES6+, AJAX & API's REST and GraphQL, Animation (Greensock & Babylon.js), Graphing (d3.js) & Realtime (websockets and socket.io), Next.js, Netlify Functions, OAuth, Git.
- React: hooks, context, router, Tanstack Query, Redux
- Testing: TypeScript, Cypress, Vitest, Vite
- Node.js: Vanilla & Express.
- Databases: SQL Postgres, NoSQL MongoDB with Mongoose.js, Firebase, GraphQL and Hygraph.
- DevOps: Docker, Vercel (inc. pipelines), serverless (inc. Netlify).
- CSS 3: Responsive design, Flexbox & CSS Grid, Material UI, Tailwind, Bootstrap, Figma.
- HTML5: Semantically correct for accessibility and SEO.

KEY PROJECTS

Title: Football Shop and Blog - https://full-stack-app-livid.vercel.app/

Tech Used: Next.js, Material UI, GraphQL, Hygraph, React Hook Form, Tanstack Query, Sendgrid,

Mongodb, Mongoose, Auth0, Dinero, Stripe

What it Does: This full stack application recreating a football e-commerce site with a blog is made using Next.js. There is shopping functionality using Tanstack Query, Dinero and Stripe. A blog has been made using GraphQL and Hygraph. Auth0 has been implemented for authentication and I've also used React Hook Form and Sendgrid to create a contact form.

Title: Drivers app - https://second-react-app-three.vercel.app/ **Tech Used**: React, Material UI, REST API, React Hook Form, Yup

What it Does: A responsive React application that shows driver contact details. The application gets data from a REST API and allows the user to perform CRUD methods. A form is created with React Hook Form, validation is performed with Yup and MUI uses theming for styling.

Title: Drinkle game - https://661e9757fb58592c764249c8--whimsical-dodol-acdd07.netlify.app/

Tech Used: Javascript using local storage

What it Does: A silly tweak on the game Wordle. Drinkle uses Javascript and local storage to allow two users to play against each other guessing randomly generated words. The loser has to drink.

EDUCATION

The Jump Digital School

Sep 2022 - May 2023

- A 30-week programme of Full-Stack Software Engineering Training
- Developed and deployed full-stack websites and web applications to a professional standard
- Delivered individual and team projects, remotely, including participation in a hackathon

University of Durham

2007 - 2010

- BA (Hons) Geography

Poole Grammar School, Dorset

2001 - 2007

- A-Levels: Geography (A), Geology (A), Maths & Statistics (B), General Studies (B)
- **GCSE's**: 4 A*'s 8A's

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

I have significant experience in digital journalism, having been heavily involved in the BBC's digital transformation, taking the lead in commissioning, filming, editing and promoting original digital video for the BBC's social media and digital platforms.

в в с

Sep 2011 - present

-	Senior Digital Producer, BBC World Service, London	Apr 2017 - present
	 Winner of 'Outstanding Digital Team of the Year' 	

the Drum Awards for 2018 and 2019

Digital Producer, BBC News, London
 Planning Producer, BBC Sports News, Manchester
 Assistant Producer, BBC Sport News, Manchester
 Sep 2011 - Jan 2014

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- I have the right to work in the UK
- Immediately available for interview
- Qualified FA Football Referee